<Document>
  # Old-kin Vox

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobOldKinVox" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to their fatal allergy to oxygen![/color]

  Like regular Vox, Old-kin also breathe nitrogen, and [color=#ffa500] oxygen is toxic to them.[/color]
  Unfortunately, space stations as well as space vessels tend to be full of oxygen.
  Due to this Vox must use an internal nitrogen supply at almost all times as well as possibly retrofit their vessels to help avoid fatal exposure.

  Vox always spawn wearing working nitrogen internals equipment.
  A spare breathing mask and an emergency nitrogen canister is provided in their survival box.

  In addition to regular foods, Vox can also eat various snack packaging, banana peels, eggshells, and raw meat without any ill effects. They also like to drink welding fuel.

  Vox [color=#1e90ff]slowly recover from low levels of poison damage[/color] on their own,
  so long as they are careful not to exceed 20 poison damage.
  This allows them to endure breathing station air for up to thirty seconds at a time without lasting damage,
  letting them quickly eat, drink, take oral medication, and so on.
  A thirty second oxygen exposure takes them two minutes to recover from.
  If their health does not seem to improve within a minute of oxygen exposure, they should seek medical attention.

  Old-kin deal Slash damage with their unarmed attack, their claws cause excess bleeding.

  Old-kin are more durable than regular Vox. Their bodies are able to handle quite a bit more punishment before collapsing. This stress slows them immensely and once taken down they succumb to their wounds much faster.
  They are more vulnerable to ambient heat as well as being stunned or exhausted, making non-lethal methods one of the more effective ways to handle one, or fire.
  Their durable bodies are more tolerant of higher and lower pressures, while this helps protect them in space they still need to breathe.


</Document>
